<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Monika Mckeown</title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000"/>
 <updated>2016-12-02T21:27:54-08:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name>Monika Mckeown</name>
   <email>mam1229@rit.edu</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>The threat of iot</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000#2016-11-26-00"/>
   <updated>2016-11-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>/The Threat of IoT</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/Internet-of-Things-Needs-IPv6-566x500.png&quot; alt=&quot;Internet-of-Things-Needs-IPv6-566x500.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://teamarin.net/2013/12/27/connected-devices-accelerate-the-need-for-ipv6-in-the-internet-of-things/&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In light of recent events with the attack on Dyn and others, the Internet of
Things is making itself known and is becoming a source of great concern. The
Internet of Things or IoT is the collection of small, cheap, disposable devices
that connect to the Internet. The FTC &lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2015/01/who-watches-the-watchers-ftc-issues-official-report-on-the-internet-of-things/&quot;&gt;defines&lt;/a&gt; the Internet of Things as “any
gadgets or sensors that transmit information about the owner over an
Internet connection—excluding gadgets like computers, smartphones,
or tablets”. Examples of gadgets range from industrial to everyday objects
and include both inanimate and living things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example home security cameras, these are useful tools used by many
people to monitor their homes both inside and out. More recently fitness
bands like Nike+ Fuel and Fitbit are becoming useful. These help you to
monitor and track your fitness activities and health. Other connected
devices like baby monitors, pacemakers and appliances are also very
useful and can make everyday life easier and provide nice comforts
unavailable before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one important thing in common with all these devices, they all
either are connected to the Internet or have wireless capabilities like
WiFi, Bluetooth or other networking technologies. This opens them to at
least temporary access to outside devices or networks. Collectively these
devices are known as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cisco.com/c/dam/en_us/solutions/trends/iot/introduction_to_IoT_november.pdf&quot;&gt;Internet of Things&lt;/a&gt;.
However these devices could also be exploited by others and used for
nefarious reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/IoTSearchEngineShodanLaunchesNewWebcamImageFeed-2-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IoTSearchEngineShodanLaunchesNewWebcamImageFeed-2-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shodan.io/host/111.39.88.62&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of these potential nefarious uses is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shodan.io/&quot;&gt;Shodon&lt;/a&gt;.
Shodon allows anyone to browse through camera feeds that have been left open
and unprotected by their primary user. The reasons they are unprotected could
be poor default settings or misconfiguration. This is just one of the more
visible examples of the emerging problems within the IoT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;potential-for-concern&quot;&gt;Potential for Concern&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individually these devices can be used to gather information on people and
other small hacking tasks to a greater extent than people realize. Like in
the example above, people might not realize what kind of information they’re
exposing to the outside world. What you can see with your security cameras so can
they. How you monitor your everyday activities so can they. While the privacy
implications here are huge, this is minor compared to the potential for damage
these devices have when exploited in large enough numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/botnet-graph.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;botnet-graph.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://resources.infosecinstitute.com/estonia-to-black-out-an-entire-country-part-one/&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The potential threat IoT devices poses for the world’s Internet infrastructure
may now be something to consider and something that might require monitoring.
These threats come primarily in the form of Distributed Denial of Service or
DDoS attacks. By &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2016/01/hacker-lexicon-what-are-dos-and-ddos-attacks/&quot;&gt;definition&lt;/a&gt;
a DDoS attack is “an attack that overwhelms a system with data—most commonly a
flood of simultaneous requests sent to a website to view its pages, causing the
web server to crash or simply become inoperable as it struggles to respond to
more requests than it can handle”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One recent major DDoS attack was conducted on Dyn. Dyn is a major DNS service
provider, serving customers like Twitter, Github and Netflix. This caused
outages across the Internet for services who depended on Dyn or it’s customers.
This was unprecedented for a DDoS originating from IoT devices. It is suspected
that the malware behind this attack and others like it is Mirai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2016/10/hacked-cameras-dvrs-powered-todays-massive-internet-outage/&quot;&gt;Mirai&lt;/a&gt;
works by “scouring the Web for IoT devices protected by little more
than factory-default usernames and passwords, and then enlists the devices in
attacks that hurl junk traffic at an online target until it can no longer
accommodate legitimate visitors or users”. The Mirai attack has brought the
concern of IoT devices to the forefront. It also gave us a view into how future
attacks might leverage the IoT to cause further damage. The source code for
Mirai is available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/James-Gallagher/Mirai&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; for
further examination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;problematic-security-in-iot&quot;&gt;Problematic security in IoT&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/broken-lock.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;broken-lock.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bitcointalkradio.com/is-bitcoin-mining-figure-joshua-zipkin-responsible-for-the-bitcointalk-hack/&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there is no one single party that can be blamed for the rise in
threats in the Internet of Things, both manufacturers and consumers play
a role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These security flaws can come from the consumer using the devices to the
manufacturers themselves. Some examples of errors made by consumers are the
use of weak firewalls, retaining &lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2016/10/inside-the-machine-uprising-how-cameras-dvrs-took-down-parts-of-the-internet/&quot;&gt;default security settings&lt;/a&gt; like access codes,
usernames or passwords. In most cases though even if the usernames and
passwords are changed these tend to be &lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/security/2014/04/how-new-malware-is-making-the-internet-of-things-the-windows-xp-of-2014/&quot;&gt;weak&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&quot;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2016/10/hacked-cameras-dvrs-powered-todays-massive-internet-outage/&quot;&gt;easy&lt;/a&gt;
to figure out, these devices can still usually be reached through connections
that are not very user friendly like Telnet and SSH. Most customers are
unaware of these capabilities. Another vulnerability found on the consumer
end is leaving DNS proxies open to the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the manufacturers side of things, the scenery isn’t much better. The
most prominent issue is one of software updates. Most of these devices are
of limited capabilities for user interaction, most of the time invisible
or out of the mind of the user. This makes any potential update mechanisms
hard to implement. Additionally the low cost of most of these devices leaves
the manufacturer with little option but to abandon support for the device
and develop a new device to sell with updated software instead. So for
these manufacturers there is really no incentive to provide software updates
that include fixes to security vulnerabilities or other improvements. The
vulnerability gets larger because while people are purchasing the newer
version there are lots of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/unite/2015/10/the-future-is-the-internet-of-things-deal-with-it/&quot;&gt;older ones&lt;/a&gt;
around and they may still be connected to the Internet. Another large problem
from the manufacturers is the inability to change settings like usernames or
passwords. This leaves customers with no protection &lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2016/10/inside-the-machine-uprising-how-cameras-dvrs-took-down-parts-of-the-internet/&quot;&gt;even if they sought&lt;/a&gt;
it out themselves. These vulnerabilities helped to make the Mirai attack on
Dyn and others a success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;moving-forward&quot;&gt;Moving Forward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good step forward would be the establishment of a set of potential
guidelines for manufacturers to follow. One such set of guidelines that they
can follow and is recommended to do so by it’s author the FTC. These
guidelines suggest employee training on the importance of security,
prioritized security through the design process, and providing constant
security updates to devices. These are just a few of the suggestions but
these could &lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2015/01/who-watches-the-watchers-ftc-issues-official-report-on-the-internet-of-things/&quot;&gt;put us further&lt;/a&gt; ahead in the current situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I different industry group known as “I Am The Cavalry” has &lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/security/2016/01/how-to-search-the-internet-of-things-for-photos-of-sleeping-babies/&quot;&gt;proposed&lt;/a&gt; their
own suggestion that being a rating system that is based off requirements like
“No default passwords shared between devices, or weak out of the box
passwords.” and  “Communication between devices should be encrypted to
prevent MitM attacks and sniffing/snooping.” While to some of us in the
computer security industry see these requirements as common sense, it is
clear that IoT manufactures do not see these things as common sense or
necessary for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we do not act however the consequences will be devastating and it’s
potential threat will continue to grow more every day. Those who use the
IoT to conduct their work go unchecked. As the number of devices that
are included in the IoT increases, the capabilities of both the devices
and the Internet make this threat even larger. What the future holds is
what we as consumers, manufacturers, and government decide to do from
this point on. The situation could either get gravely worse, or improve. We
will just have to see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
